<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>I Will - I Can </title><link>https://example.com/</link><description>Read Write Loop and Teach</description><atom:link href="https://example.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:dwisianto@gmail.com"&gt;Dwi Sianto&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 03:21:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Lifelong principles</title><link>https://example.com/posts/21/06/06/lifelong-principles/</link><dc:creator>Dwi Sianto</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I summarize a few lifelong principles I have lived by for my sons who are growing up everyday . 
My words and my actions over the year should have introduced these principles to them. These principles hopefully can carry them to adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hobby - Make time for yourself.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobby is a kind of constructive activities that can be enjoyed in our leisure time and give us happiness and joy.
Constructive activities channels positive energy into our body and mind. There are many type of constructive hobbies such as reading, writing, swimming, drawing, gardening, and playing a piano. 
The feeling of joy and happiness is usually followed by a sense of accomplishment. Thus, hobby usually led to a productive &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A constructive hobby can be enjoyed everyday. It can be started from childhood, be performed at own pace, and can be developed at any age till the end of life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
Hobby Essay 6 (400 words)

Hobby is a good thing a person gets from childhood. It can be developed at any age however best to get from childhood. We all do some kind of work according to our interest which can give us happiness and joy that is called hobby. Some people get different hobbies according to their interest, likes and dislikes. There are many type of hobbies we can develop such as dancing, singing, drawing, playing indoor or outdoor game, bird watching, collecting antiques, photography, writing, eating, reading, sports, playing, gardening, music, watching TV, cooking, talking, and so many. Our hobbies help us in earning live hood and make a successful career. Hobby is something we can fully enjoy in our leisure or free time.

My favourite is cooking, listening music and gardening however I always prefer gardening. Gardening is like meditation to me which improves my work efficiency, interest and ability. It gives me high level of peace and makes my whole day useful. Every early morning I enjoy my blooming garden, growing plants slowly on daily basis. I also enjoy sun rise and sun set daily in my garden. I generally like to do my school home work in my evergreen garden. I play badminton with my father daily in the evening in my garden and enjoy evening walk with my mom. I daily watch new plants development and do watering plant. I also try planting new and decorative plants to my garden in order to enhance its look and beauty.

I am 14 years old and read in class 9th standard. I want to continue my favourite hobbies till the end of my life. They would keep me busy, happy and away from all tensions of the daily life. My parents always promote me to continue my all hobbies. They become so happy when I take my problems in easy way and try to solve them without getting anger and tension. My mom says that gardening is a good hobby than other ones; it blesses us because we give life to someone through watering and planting new plants. From my childhood I work daily in my garden for one hour to keep it well maintained. I have made there a nice and attractive green carpet using velvet grass. I have prepared beautiful flowerbeds in every corner of the garden and planted colourful roses, lilies, mogra, sunflowers, and other seasonal flowers.
--&gt;

&lt;!-- 

# Integrity - Anything achieved without integrity is not worth achieving. 

I learnt this early on from my father. My father was a man of few words, and he hardly would impart any ‘wisdom’ as a father son conversation. But I remember this incident so well, when I was a little boy, may be in 2nd or 3rd grade, I had made a beautiful drawing on a slate with a chalk. Those were the days where we used slates to write using chalk. The only chalk we could afford were the plain and simple white ones. But my drawing had colors, blue and green and yellow, meticulously done with colorful chalks. 

As I showed the drawing to my father, hoping for him to praise me for the drawing, the first question he asked was where did I get the colorful chalks? I got them from school I remember saying. He handed over the slate to me, saying the chalks belonged to school, why did you bring them home – that’s stealing. I was heart-broken at the time, not getting the praise for my drawing which I had hoped so much, one which I had put so much effort, but I later realized how important that lesson had been. Every small action counts, even when they are left-over chalks belonging to school. If you did not earn it, the achievements don’t matter.




# There is no substitute for hard work - Thomas Edison


There is no substitute for hard work and perseverance – let that hard work be for your passion.

Hard work and perseverance – always wins, the key to ‘your’ success is that you are putting that hard work for things that matter to you. The stuff you are passionate about. Remember, hard work without passion is just stress!


# Perserverances - When you start something, finish it.

These are offshoot words from the traditional wisdom of persistence. I remember since he was a small boy, I used this phrase. I don’t know why, may be ‘persistence’ was a big word for him at that time. The quote stuck – throughout his growing up and he has lived by this all his life. As he matured, he has argued, often successfully, that sometime, you have to abandon a project which you know enough that it will not lead to the outcome. Over time we had come to a conclusion together – that ‘failure’ is actually a right outcome for many actions as long as we deliberately finish an action with learning from those abandonment.



# Don’t just know the trick of the trade, know the trade.

Another one of my Cliché Quotes – don’t look for shortcuts or knowing enough to get by. Put yourself fully in whatever you are doing – there is no substitute for knowledge. 

He learnt this early on – I remember this incident when he was in sixth grade and wanted to build a computer for himself. We went to Fry’s electronics and he picked all the components which were needed for building that PC. The store rep – surprised at us, letting the boy potentially spoil 100s of dollars-worth of components, offered that Fry’s technician can build it for fifty bucks. We of course declined their offer. 

That was probably the best thousand dollars I have ever invested – he went on building several such PCs during middle school and eventually learnt to program and as he goes to do engineering this fall, I hope the quote stays with him as it has been thus far!


# Be Real.

In this world of social media, fake news, hyper show off, being real is the new ‘Fake it till you make it.’ (btw I always hated this term). Be yourself, that does not mean don’t market yourself, but market ‘your true self’. Your work will make you shine – not what you put for a show (on social media or any professional media).



# Fame - Don’t let others define your measure of success

Remember, money, fame, or whatever other measure what the world defines as success is the other people’s measurement of success. 

Don’t let others define your success. 

You define your success – once you define it – follow it with all your passion.

--&gt;

&lt;!--

# There is nothing more important than family and friends.

And finally – the moto I have lived through out my life. And it has never been more evident than during this Pandemic. The work will come and go – what stays with you is your values and relationships. Everything else is not important.

I am proud to have raised two young boys – and am so confident as he enters the world of adulthood, the values I jotted down above are not new to him, he has lived them thus far and I know he will in future, as he enters this new phase of his life.

--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/my-son-prepares-enter-new-phase-life-ashok-kumar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://lifegoalsmag.com/7-reasons-why-having-a-hobby-is-important-25-ideas-to-get-you-started/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>lifelong</category><guid>https://example.com/posts/21/06/06/lifelong-principles/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>